{"name": "69A  2010-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Mr. Chiang announced the grade distribution for this week's book reports. Of the 24 students in the class, 8 received A's for their book reports, 11 received B's, and 5 received C's. When a student is chosen at random to be the first one to read his or her book report to the class, what is the probability that the student chosen had received an A for the book report?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. A puzzle board with a 3-foot-by-4-foot rectangular top surface is to be made from cedar. The cedar has a price of $3 per square foot of top surface area. What is the price of the cedar needed to make this puzzle board?", "choices": {"A": "$15", "B": "$21", "C": "$36", "D": "$42", "E": "$72"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. A point at (-5,8) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane is shifted right 8 units and down 5 units. What are the new coordinates of the point?", "choices": {"A": "(-13,13)", "B": "(  0, 0)", "C": "(  3, 3)", "D": "(  3, 13)", "E": "( 13, 13)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. A warehouse dispatcher is arranging the delivery of 83,000 condensers. She will use 2 large-size trucks, each carrying a maximum of 18,000 condensers. The remaining trucks are small-size trucks, each carrying a maximum of 7,000 condensers. Each truck she uses will make exactly 1 trip. Along with the 2 large-size trucks, what is the minimum number of small-size trucks needed to deliver all the condensers?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "7", "D": "9", "E": "10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. A positive integer x is divisible by 15, 25, and 30. Which of the following is the smallest possible value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "75", "B": "90", "C": "120", "D": "150", "E": "450"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. In \u25b3ABC, \u2220A and \u2220C are congruent, and the measure of \u2220B is 96\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "42\u00b0", "B": "48\u00b0", "C": "60\u00b0", "D": "84\u00b0", "E": "96\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. What is the value of x in the equation -2(x - 7) = 20 ?", "choices": {"A": "-13.5", "B": "-6.5", "C": "-3", "D": "3", "E": "17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. For all real values of x, which of the following is equal to x3\u00b7 x3 \u00b7 x3 \u00b7 x3  ?", "choices": {"A": "x12", "B": "x81", "C": "3x4", "D": "4x3", "E": "(4x)3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. What is 10% of 10% of 1 ?", "choices": {"A": "0.001", "B": "0.01", "C": "0.1", "D": "1.0", "E": "10.0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Use the following information to answer questions 10-12.The table below gives the price per gallon of unleaded gasoline at Gus's Gas Station on January 1 for 5 consecutive years in the 1990s. At Gus's, a customer can purchase a car wash for $4.00.10. What is the mean price per gallon, to the nearest $0.01, on January 1 for the 5 years listed in the table?", "choices": {"A": "$1.25", "B": "$1.33", "C": "$1.34", "D": "$1.35", "E": "$1.41"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Use the following information to answer questions 10-12.The table below gives the price per gallon of unleaded gasoline at Gus's Gas Station on January 1 for 5 consecutive years in the 1990s. At Gus's, a customer can purchase a car wash for $4.00.11. The price for gas on January 1 of Year 6 was 3% higher than the price on January 1 of Year 5. To the nearest $0.01, how much was the price per gallon on January 1 of Year 6?", "choices": {"A": "$1.39", "B": "$1.40", "C": "$1.66", "D": "$1.77", "E": "$2.39"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Use the following information to answer questions 10-12.The table below gives the price per gallon of unleaded gasoline at Gus's Gas Station on January 1 for 5 consecutive years in the 1990s. At Gus's, a customer can purchase a car wash for $4.00.12.On January 1 of Year 5, Anamosa bought gas and a car wash at Gus's. She put 11.38 gallons of gas in her car and 1.85 gallons of gas in a container for her snowblower. To the nearest $0.01, how much did Anamosa pay for the gas for her car and snowblower, and a car wash?", "choices": {"A": "$15.48", "B": "$17.23", "C": "$17.99", "D": "$19.48", "E": "$21.99"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. What is the value of |x + y| + (x + y)2 when x = 2 and y = -3?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "-4", "C": "-2", "D": "0 ", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The decimal representation of 3. 9 x 10-93 is:", "choices": {"A": "a decimal point, followed by 92 zeros, then the digits 3 and 9.", "B": "a decimal point, followed by 93 zeros, then the digits 3 and 9.", "C": "a negative sign, followed by the digits 3 and 9, then 92 zeros, then a decimal point.", "D": "a negative sign, followed by the digits 3 and 9, then 93 zeros, then a decimal point.", "E": "a negative sign, followed by the digits 3 and 9, then 94 zeros, then a decimal point."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The number of bricks, B, needed to build a wall of length L feet and uniform height H feet can be found by the equation B = 7LH. A wall of uniform height that is 15 feet long is constructed using 525 bricks. What is the height, in feet, of the wall?", "choices": {"A": " 0.5", "B": "3.5", "C": "5", "D": "35", "E": "75"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the value of g(x) = (-3)x +3 when x=2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "-3", "C": "0 ", "D": "9", "E": "12"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. (5c - 3d)(2d - 5c) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "-cd", "B": "25cd", "C": "-25c2 - 5cd - 6d2", "D": "-25c2 + 25cd - 6d2", "E": "-6c2d2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In the figure below, AC and BE intersect at D. What is the measure of \u2220EAD ?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "47\u00b0", "C": "50\u00b0", "D": "53\u00b0", "E": "70\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  The sum of the real numbers x  and y is 21. Their difference is 15. What is the value of xy ?", "choices": {"A": " 18", "B": "21", "C": " 36", "D": "54", "E": "315"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. After visiting Mountain State University during spring break, Meredith rents a car for 1 day to travel around the area. She has $100 to spend on car rental. Green Tree Car Rental charges $50 per day and $0.25 per mile. Big Rock Car Rental charges $60 per day and $0.20 per mile. Which company, if either, allows her to travel more miles, and how many miles more ?(Note: Taxes are already included in the rental charges. )", "choices": {"A": "Green Tree, 25", "B": "Green Tree, 40", "C": "Big Rock, 10", "D": "Big Rock, 100", "E": "Meredith would get the same maximum number of miles from each company."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. For x2 \u2260 25\uff0c= ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The directions for punch call for 3 cups of juice concentrate to be mixed with 5 cups of water. If the directions are followed, how many cups of juice concentrate will be needed to make 80 cups of punch?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "32", "C": "40", "D": "48", "E": "50"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following inequalities is true for the fractions , and  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. As part of a lesson on motion, students observed a cart rolling at a constant rate along a straight line. As shown in the chart below, they recorded the distance, y feet, of the cart from a reference point at 1-second intervals from t = 0 seconds to t = 5 seconds.Which of the following equations represents this data?", "choices": {"A": "y = t + 12", "B": "y = 8t + 4", "C": "y = 8t + 12", "D": "y = 12t + 8", "E": "y = 20t"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. A tortoise moves x times as fast as a snail. A hare moves y times as fast as the tortoise. The hare moves how many times as fast as the snail?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "xy", "D": "y - x", "E": "y + x "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The line shown below in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane is represented by one of the following equations. Which one is it ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. A group of 25 cells triples in number every hour. At this rate, how many cells will be in the group at the end of the 5th hour?", "choices": {"A": "125", "B": "375", "C": "3,125", "D": "6,075", "E": "9,375"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Two triangles are similar. The shortest side of the smaller triangle is 9 inches long, and the shortest side of the larger triangle is 16 inches long. The perimeter of the smaller triangle is 36 inches, What is the perimeter, in inches, of the larger triangle?", "choices": {"A": "43", "B": "48", "C": "57", "D": "61", "E": "64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. At a produce market, apples sell for $1.00 per bag and oranges for $1.75 per bag. The fruit is only sold in whole bags. You plan to buy at least 1 bag of each fruit and spend exactly $16.00. What is the maximum number of bags of oranges you can buy?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "8", "E": "9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the vertex of the parabola with the equation y = 2(x - 3)2- 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "(-3, -5)", "B": "(-3, 5)", "C": "(3, -5)", "D": "(3, 5)", "E": "(6, -5)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. A diameter of a circle in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane has endpoints at (2, 8) and (-2, 6). Which of the following points is the center of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "(0, 2)", "B": "(0, 7)", "C": "(0, 14)", "D": "(2, 1) ", "E": "(4, 2)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. What is the circumference, in centimeters, of a circle with a radius of 6 cm ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "3\u03c0", "C": "9\u03c0", "D": "12\u03c0", "E": "36\u03c0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the figure below, point B lies on side AC of rectangle ACDE. Line segments AD and BD are also shown. The given lengths are in inches.33. How many inches long is BC ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "14", "C": "20", "D": "36", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the figure below, point B lies on side AC of rectangle ACDE. Line segments AD and BD are also shown. The given lengths are in inches.34. Which of the following is an expression for sin \u2220CDA ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the figure below, point B lies on side AC of rectangle ACDE. Line segments AD and BD are also shown. The given lengths are in inches.35. Point B is reflected across the line (not shown) that connects the midpoints of AE and CD. This reflection of B is labeled F. How many inches from AC is the intersection of CF and BD \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "8", "C": "", "D": "15", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. In the diagram below, B, F, and H are on AC, AE, and BF, respectively, and GH \u22a5 BF. The area of square ABGF is the area of ACDE. The area of \u25b3FGH is what fraction of the area of ACDE ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. The first 3 terms of an arithmetic sequence are , , and , in that order. What is the fourth term of the sequence ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Given the equations B = x + 2 and y = A - 4, which of the following expressions is equivalent to B + A written in terms of x and y ?", "choices": {"A": "x + y + 2", "B": "x + y + 6", "C": "x - y - 4", "D": "8xy", "E": "2x + 4y"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The perimeter of a parallelogram is 64 inches, and 1 side measures 10 inches. If it can be determined, what are the lengths, in inches, of the other 3 sides ?", "choices": {"A": "10, 10, 34", "B": "10, 17, 17", "C": "10, 22, 22", "D": "10, 27, 27", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Given that m, n, and a are positive integers, which of he following statements is true whenever am &lt; (-a)n ?", "choices": {"A": "m = n and n is odd", "B": "m \uff1c n and n is odd", "C": "m \uff1c n and n is even", "D": "m \uff1e n and n is odd", "E": "m \uff1e n and n is even"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. In quadrilateral ABCD shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, what is the distance, in coordinate units, from the midpoint of AD to the midpoint of CD ?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. In rhombus ACBD below, AB is 8 inches long and CD is 6 inches long. What is the area, in square inches, of ACBD ?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "24", "C": "25", "D": "32", "E": "48"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. In how many distinct orders can 5 students stand in line to buy yearbooks \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "15", "C": "25", "D": "120", "E": "3,125"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. A group of hikers put up the tent shown below. They draped a rectangular tarp that is 10 feet by 12 feet over a rope stretched tightly between 2 trees so that the tent's rectangular sides and base are each 6 feet wide and 10 feet long. What is the height of the tent, to the nearest foot ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Which of the following statements gives the real number values of x for which x2 \uff1c x is true ?", "choices": {"A": "0 \uff1c x \uff1c 1", "B": "-1 \uff1c x \uff1c 1", "C": "x \uff1c -1", "D": "x \uff1e 1", "E": "x = 0 or x = 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. A teacher asked all the students in the junior class about the number of cats and/or dogs their family had. The results are given in the table below. How many students answered that their family had 1 or more cats ?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "114", "C": "132", "D": "198", "E": "250"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The Worthwhile Company's logo consists of 2 concentric circles. The radius of the outer circle of the logo on Worthwhile's building is 4 feet, and the distance between the outer circle and the inner circle is 1.75 feet. Which of the following is an expression for the area, in square feet, of the inner circle of the logo on Worthwhile's building?", "choices": {"A": "(4 - 1.75)2\u03c0", "B": "(4 - 1.75)\u03c0", "C": "(42 - 1.752)\u03c0", "D": "2(4 - 1.75)2\u03c0", "E": "2(4 - 1.75)\u03c0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Given that A,B,C, and D are real numbers satisfying A = B, C2 = D, and C = , which of the following equations is NOT necessarily true?", "choices": {"A": "A = C", "B": "A = D", "C": "B = D", "D": "B = C2", "E": "B2 = D2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The volume, V, of a right circular cylinder with radius r and height h is given by the formula V= \u03c0r2h. The right circular cylinder shown below has radius R and height H. A second right circular cylinder has radius 2R and height 3H. The volume of the second right circular cylinder is how many times the volume of the first right circular cylinder ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "7", "D": "12", "E": "18"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. For right triangle \u25b3ABC, sin\u2220A =.  What is cos \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. The line with equation x - 4y = 12 in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane crosses the x-axis at which of the following points ?", "choices": {"A": " (-12, 0)", "B": "(-4, -4)", "C": "(-4, 0)", "D": "(0, 3)", "E": "(12, 0)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Alexia knows that the height of an object propelled vertically from a height of 48 feet can be modeled by h = -16t2 + 32t + 48, where h is the height, in feet, and t is the time, in seconds. Using this model, how many seconds will it take the object to reach a height of 64 feet?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "16", "E": "64"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. In the figure below,is parallel to , B lies onand , F lies on , the measure of \u2220ABC is 132\u00b0, and \u2220EBG \u2245 \u2220GBF \u2245\u2220FBD. What is the measure of \u2220BFD ?", "choices": {"A": "84\u00b0", "B": "86\u00b0", "C": "88\u00b0", "D": "89\u00b0", "E": "92\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. For a certain angle with measure \ud835\udec9, sin \ud835\udec9=0. 4. What is csc \ud835\udec9?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Simpsen Manufacturing tested the hydraulic pressure capacity of 2 brands of valves, Valve A and Valve B, on their hydraulic pressure pump. Valve B allowed a slower decrease in pressure than Valve A followed by a slower increase in pressure than Valve A. The minimum pressure for Valve A was Iess than the minimum pressure for Valve B. One of the following graphs best illustrates the test results. Which graph is it \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Happy Soup Company stamps a 6-character product code on each can of soup it produces. Each product code consists of 5 letters (from the 26-letter alphabet) followed by a single digit (from the digits 0 to 9). The letters may repeat. How many such product codes are possible ?", "choices": {"A": "5(26)(10)", "B": "5(4)(3)(2)", "C": "15(10)", "D": "26(25)(24)(23)(22)(10)", "E": "265(10)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. For all real numbers x, the value of x - |x| is:", "choices": {"A": "never zero.", "B": "always zero.", "C": "always positive.", "D": "sometimes positive.", "E": "never positive."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For all values of x such that sin x &gt; 0 and cos x &gt;0, which of the following expressions is equivalent to \\frac{1}{2}cos\\,x\"> ?", "choices": {"A": "\\frac{1}{2}\">", "B": " \\frac{1}{2}\">", "C": " cos x- sin x \uff1c2", "D": "\\frac{1}{2}\">", "E": "tan x \uff1c2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. A vector from the origin to terminal point (2, 3) is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The vector will be rotated counterclockwise (\u293a) by 90\u00b0 about the origin, resulting in a new vector. What will be the coordinates of the terminal point of the new vector ?", "choices": {"A": "(-3, 2)", "B": "(-2, -3)", "C": "(-2, 3)", "D": "(2, -3)", "E": "(3, -2)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. If r &gt; 0 and s &gt; 0,  is equivalent to which of the following ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}]}